ACTWU's Social Services Department Records 5619/023
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACTWU's Social Services Department Records
1960-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. Amalgamated Social Services
Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Amalgamated Social Services
Rosenthal, Deena Foreman
5619/023
45.33 cubic feet
45.3 linear ft.
Correspondence, reports, publications.
This collection consists of correspondence, reports, publications, research materials, and files from the office of Deena Foreman Rosenthal, Amalgamated Social Services Director for Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America and for Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union.
6832656
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
April 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, May 2011
Biographical / Historical
The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City in 1914 as a breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in the tailors' and cutters' locals were the core of the seceding group, which advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW's craft organization, which they saw as conservative and timid. Their diverging views had come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition called the strike against the UGW leadership's advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an arbitration system to settle disputes.
Members flocked to the new union. Around 50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the ACWA counted about 170,000 members. Initially composed mostly of immigrants of Jewish European descent with Socialist leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members of a great number of nationalities and diverse backgrounds. Like in other garment unions, most workers and many members were women, but the leadership was predominantly male, a situation that did not change for many decades. Early on the union adopted a centralized administrative structure combined with industrial unionism, with the joint boards' by-laws having precedence over those of locals.
Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its early immigrant socialist members, the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter issues and adopted a distinctive form of social unionism that was largely absent in the American labor movement. Starting in the 1920s, it provided educational opportunities and recreational facilities for its members, as well as services such as an insurance plan, banks offering personal loans at low interest rates, low-cost housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and even union-owned restaurants.
Sidney Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important officer in its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative in Chicago to the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant strides in securing better wages and working conditions for its members, and at the same time it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the widespread adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. Hillman paid close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and marketing. In order to help management meet the competition of non-union firms, the union conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to the official publication of the union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management.
Hillman also understood the importance of labor's involvement in national affairs and political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the Conference for Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although many members and officers were Socialists, the union stopped short of officially endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were firmly curbed. Hillman's participation in national affairs and politics became prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D. Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. He also served on the board of the National Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor's Non Partisan League. He was also named associate director of the Office of Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the war effort. Hillman's prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union, which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable.
During the post World War II period the union faced a number of significant challenges. Membership continued to grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), but the union's political influence and visibility in national affairs declined. In their never ending pursuit of lower production costs, many firms relocated to the South, forcing the union to engage in large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began to appear of changes that would lead to the almost complete demise of the domestic apparel industry and, ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign imports of cheap clothing goods steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed in the following two decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a steady decline. Union efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and extensive lobbying in Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged with the Textile Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such as the Farah boycott and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the union's existence continued unabated. The fate of the domestic industry was sealed in the late 1970s and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap labor abroad. By 1995, when ACTWU voted to merge with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new life in a troubled union.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related collections: 5619: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America And all other 5619 collections.
Textile workers -- Labor unions; Clothing workers -- Labor unions; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees. Amalgamated Social Services; UNITE HERE (Organization)
6832656
- SSD Copyright, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adelaide Mills, Anaston, Alabama, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Masland Carpets Local 1882 - Atmore, Alabama, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- South Alabama Joint Board Local 992 Brantley, Alabama, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- South Regional Joint Board - White Hosp. Supply, Camp Hill, Alabama - Local 1052, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cordova Mills, Local 2298, Cordova, Alabama, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Fabrics America: closing 1983 Alabama: Enterprise Number 2337, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Evergreen, Alabama, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Georgiana Social Services Committee, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Elvin Odom Local Number 1065 (Alabama Joint Board), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Guntersville, Alabama Number 1926 (Standard, Coosa Thatcher) Layoff, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mobile, Alabama - Local 1465, Courtalds, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mobile, Alabama, Local 1465 Courtalds, NA, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Mount Vernon, Alabama Local 1465, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Opelika Manufacturing; Layoffs 1985 Alabama: Opelika Number 1840 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Palm Beach Company Alabama: Number 613 Roanoke Plant Closing 1983, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Gurney Manufacturing, Alabama, Prattville, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Alabama: Scottsboro Number 2321 and 2321A (Ballet Fabrics and Bellefonte Lace), 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Scottsboro, Alabama - Bellefonte Lace 2321A, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Eagle of Alabama Number 1093C Plant Closing, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Number 990-991- C Troy Plant Closing, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- South Regional Joint Board, Miss. Sub. Reg. York, Alabama - Local 1068, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Winfield, Alabama - Local 943-C South Regional Joint Board ©, N. AL Reg., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Arkansas District, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Arkansas Local 1048, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Local 1157, Lake Village, Arkansas, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Arkansas: Leachville Shoe Local Number 264, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Arkansas: Number 1078, Junction City Plant Closing, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Local 799 Warren, Arkansas, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- California Joint Board LA Zody's Closing, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- California Joint Board/ LA, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Local 818 T Carlsbad, California, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Local 730 - Fresno, California (Box 1, Folder 33)
- California: San Diego, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Montreal Joint Board, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Quebec, Drummondville - Local 1626 Refridgerateurs Foster du Canada, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Rocky Mountain District Joint Board - Denver, Colorado, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Colorado, Greely Local 731 Bayly Corporation, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Colorado, Colorado Springs Local 2333, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Local 1171, Denver, Colorado, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Colorado, Denver, Local 2381 AMF - Head, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Local 125 Branford, Connecticut New England Regional Sero, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Connecticut: New Haven Social Service Committee, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Local 1732, Sterling, Connecticut Revere Textile, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Connecticut, Willimantic, Southern New England Joint Board, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Willimantic, Connecticut Atco, Local 460T, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Delaware: Newark Number 1706 Strike Support, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- District of Columbia: Upper South Regional Credit Union, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Southern Alabama Regional Board, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Local 2461 Leesburg Apparel, Leesburg, Florida, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Local 509 Ocala Florida South Region - Silver Springs Sportswear, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Georgia: Georgia Joint Board, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Georgia: Southern Regional Joint Board College Park, Georgia, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Georgia: Augusta United Merchants; organizing, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Georgia, Canton Canton Textiles, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Local 1855, Columbus, Georgia Fieldcrest, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Columbus, Georgia - Local 1855 South Textile Region - Fieldcrest, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Georgia: Number 1055 Hawkinsville Plant Closing, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Georgia - Hawkinsville Local 2448 Opelika Manufacturing, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Louisville, Georgia - Local 2526 Central Alabama/Georgia - Delilah, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Macon, Georgia Local 2437 TexPrint Central Alabama Joint Board (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Macon, Georgia Local 2399 Stealth Apparel, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Georgia, Statesboro, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Georgia: Sylvester Opelika Manufacturing, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Waynesboro, Georgia Local 2524 Central Alabama/Georgia - Sampson, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Local 1437 Chicago, Illinois, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Chicago and Central States Joint Board Illinois, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Chicago Joint Board Textile Division, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Illinois, Cairo Number 952, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Local 200 A - Carlyle, Illinois Shoe Division - Trimfoot, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Illinois: Charleston Local 202 Samuel Shoe Company, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Herrin, Illinois - Local 1374 Chicago Joint Board - Sheller-Globe Corporation, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Illinois: Knoxville Number 465 Social Services, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Illinois Park Forest Number 1893 Johnson and Johnson, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Illinois - Pittsfield - Local 2443, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Illinois: Rock Island Number 617 Social Services, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Indiana: East Chicago Number 83 Social Services (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Indiana: Rochester Number 785 Childcare, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Local 2450/2335 - South Whitley and Kendallville, Ind., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Iowa: Mason City Number 568 Social Service (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Local 685, Southwest Region Seymour, Indiana, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Local Union 610, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Paris, Kentucky - Local 1079 East Tennessee/Kentucky Sub-Regional Office, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Kentucky: Louisvill3 (and New Albany Ind.) Social Services Kentuckiana JB, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Louisiana: Haynesville Number 1000, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Louisiana: New Orleans Local 1002 Social Services, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Maine Joint Board New England Region, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Edwards Manufacturing Augusta, Maine Number 494T, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Maine: Biddeford Number 406 West Point Pepperell, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Maine: Brunswick Number 725 Social Service Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Maine: Portland Number 667 Social Service Committee, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Maine: Waterville, Local 120T Wyandotte Ind., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Maine: Social Services Conference: Portland (Clothing and Textile jointly), 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Social Services Department, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Maryland: Cambridge Number 107 Social Services Committee, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Maryland: Eastern Shore Joint Board. General Correspondence (Cambridge, Salisbury, Rock Hall), 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- D and F Shirt (Salisbury, Maryland) ALICO Claims - Unemployment Fund, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- SMI (Salisbury, Maryland) ALICO Claims - Unemployment, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Local 853 C Baltimore Joint Board Hancock, Maryland, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Local 1874 (Cumberland, Maryland), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Maryland: Rock Hall Number 754 (Eastern Shore Joint Board) Clothing, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 101)
- Maryland: Salisbury Locals 383C, 1046, 1047 East Shore Joint Board Social Service Committee, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- Local Number 149 Hagerstown, Maryland, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 103)
- Baltimore Regional Joint Board, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 104)
- New England Regional Joint Board, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Massachusetts: Easthampton Number 523, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Local 1057, Fall River Massachusetts, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Fall River, Massachusetts - United Merchants, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Massachusetts: Fitchburg Number 309 Social Services Committee, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Massachusetts: Lawrence Number 187 Social Services Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Local 2, (Shoe Division) Lynn, Massachusetts, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Massachusetts: New Bedford Fall River: Social Services, 1977-1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Massachusetts - Worcester Local 300T, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Michigan: Detroit Number 124 Social Services, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Michigan: Ironwood Number 1890 Social Services Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Midwest Regional Office, St. Louis Missouri, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Minnesota Joint Board, St. Paul, Minnesota, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Social Services/ Twin Cities, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Minnesota, Minneapolis Local 66 Munsingwear, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Minnesota: Little Falls Number 1254 Strike Support Munsingwear, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Minnesota: Montgomery Number 1256 Social Services Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Minnesota: Northfield Number 1481 Social Service Committee, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Mississippi: Tylertown Social Services, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Local Union 643 Water Valley, Mississippi, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Local 88 and 282 - Aurora, Missouri Local 214A - Carthage, Missouri Shoe Division, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Bloomfield and Dexter, Missouri Locals Southwest Regional Joint Board - Elder, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Local 970, Bolivar, Missouri, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Local 288 Herman, Missouri, St. Louis District Florsheim Shoe, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Murphysboro, Missouri Southwest Regional Joint Board, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Local 245/ Owensville, Missouri, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Local 451, St. Joseph, Missouri, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Sikeston, Missouri - Local 2432 Southwest Regional/ St. Louis - Grove Manufacturing, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Southwest Regional Joint Board, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Missouri, St. Louis - Shoe Division, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Unitog, St. Louis District, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Midwest Regional Joint Board, St. Louis, Missouri, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Tipton, Missouri - Local 260 Southwest Regional Joint Board Biltwell, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Locals 1106, 930 Cape Giradeau, Missouri, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Chaffee, Missouri - Local 930 Cape Girardeau Joint Board - Thorngate, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Nebraska: Fremont Number 1008 Social Service Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Nebraska: Nebraska City, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Berkshire - Hathaway, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- New Hampshire: Manchester Number 359 Social Service Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- New Jersey: Hammonton Number 217 (South Jersey Joint Board), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Paramount Industries Plainfield, New Jersey, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- New Jersey: Crticon Raritan Number 1651, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- New Jersey: South Jersey Joint Board Vineland, New Jersey, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Ethicon Plant Number 630 Somerville, New Jersey, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- New Jersey, Skilman Number 2269 T, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Local 1363 T Central and South Jersey Joint Board, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Local 26T Central and South Jersey Joint Board, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- New Jersey: Beverly Number 944T Wall Rope, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- New Jersey; Cape May Number 2316 Rio Grande, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Jersey City, New Jersey - Local 2442 Headwear Trio Accessories, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Passaic, New Jersey - Local 24-42 Headwear Grossman and Son, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Perth Amboy, New Jersey - Local 169 Schott Bros., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Union City, New Jersey - Local 2H Headwear Goldstar Hats and Caps, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- New Brunswick, New Jersey - Local 1298 Central/ South Jersey - Permacel, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Buffalo, New York Unemployment Program, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Gloversville, New York Social Services Committee, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- New York City Capmakers Number 2, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- New York: New York City Capmakers Number 24-42 Strike, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- New York: Dyers Division (T), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Local 1946 Hudson, New York, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- New York: New York City Number 169 Work Release Program Ex-Offender, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- J. P. Stevens, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- New York, Headwear and Allied Workers Joint Board, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- New York City Headwear Strike, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- New York: Hudson Valley JB, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Joint Council 13, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- New York: New York Joint Board New York City (Clothing), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- New York Joint Board, Textile Division, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- New York: Shoe Joint Board, Regina Footwear, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Local 4, New York, New York, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- New York Number 4 Upgrading/Fit., 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- New York, Amsterdam Local Union 2325 Edmund Stern Inc., 1978-1985 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- New York, Auburn Local 1085T and 2325, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Buffalo, New York, Lakeside Mills, Local 111H, Buffalo Joint Board, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Gloversville, New York Glove Cities Joint Board, Crescent Leather Corporation, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- New York City, Local 1870 T, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Local Union File, Oswego, New York Armstrong Wool Industries, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- New York: Port Jervis Number 1410; Strike Support, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Rochester, New York - Local 1800 Greater Northern Joint Board - Mailwell Corporation, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Local 3T, Rochester, New York, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Sidney Hillman Health Center, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- New York: Syracuse Number 1947 Layoff Project, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- New York, Tappan, Local 1870, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Tonawanda, New York Local 1644, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- New York: Troy Number 314, Arrow Shirt: Plant Closing, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 85)
- Local 150 Utica, New York, Greater New York Joint Board (T) Dunlop Tire, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- Carolinas-Virginia Regional Joint Board - Raleigh, North Carolina, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- Western Carolinas Joint Board, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 88)
- North Carolina: Bladenborough Social Services/ organizing, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 89)
- North Carolina, Chapel Hill MDC Study, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 90)
- North Carolina: Kannapolis Cannon Mills: Organizing, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 91)
- Tornado Damage, North Carolina, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 92)
- North Carolina, Charlotte Woonsocket Spinning Local 2351, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 93)
- North Carolina, Eden, Local 294T, Bi-County Joint Board, 1976-1982 (Box 2, Folder 94)
- Local 250-T North Carolina, Erwin, Burlington Mills, Central North Carolina Joint Board, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 95)
- North Carolina: Fletcher, Local 1355 Western Carolina Joint Board, Cranston Print Works, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 96)
- Greensboro, North Carolina Local 259 Cone Mills, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 97)
- North Carolina: Hendersonville (Box 2, Folder 98)
- Local 2376 - High Point, North Carolina, J. P. Stevens, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 99)
- North Carolina, Laurinburg, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 100)
- Mooresville, North Carolina, Armitage Shanks (newly organized), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 101)
- North Carolina: Mount Olive, Young Squire Carolina Regional Joint Board Number 1113C, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 102)
- North Carolina: Roanoke Rapids Credit Union, Roanoke Valley Joint Board, J. P. Stevens, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 103)
- Reidsville, North Carolina - Local 121 Central North Carolina Joint Board - Cone Mills, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 104)
- North Carolina, Roanoke Rapids, Roanoke Valley Central Labor Union, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 105)
- North Carolina, Spartanburg United Cloth Western Carolina Joint Board, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 106)
- North Carolina, Wallace J. P. Stevens, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 107)
- Whiteville, North Carolina - Local 1077 South Regional Joint Board/ Carolina-Virginia - Whiteville App Hart and Mary, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 108)
- Local 1676 T East Central North Carolina Joint Board, North Carolina, Wilmington, Deporters Corporation, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 109)
- Pennsylvania: Scranton/Wilkes-Barre District Joint Board, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Local 1056 - Local 1088 Pennsylvania, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)